ford.ca 2017-06-27

# privacy

## FORD MOTOR COMPANY OF CANADA, LIMITED   
PRIVACY POLICY

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. This privacy policy explains our policies and practices regarding customer information, including why we collect customer information, how we use and safeguard it, and how you can contact us to access your customer information or if you have any questions or concerns about our privacy practices. Please take the time to read this privacy policy. By using this site, you agree to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with our Privacy Policy, please do not provide us with any personal information. If you are interested in our collection of information on our website, please [click here to go to How We Collect Information on our Website.](http://www.ford.ca/help/privacy/#HOW_COLLECT_INFO_WEBSITE)

### Table of Contents:

  * Information about Ford of Canada
  * How to Contact Us and Concern Resolution
  * Why We Collect and How We Use Customer Information
  * Types of Customer Information We Collect and Use
  * How We Collect Customer Information
  * How We Collect Information on our Website
  * How We Share Customer Information
  * How is Privacy Managed at Ford and Ford/Lincoln Dealers in Canada
  * How You Can Opt Out of Further Marketing Communications
  * Security and Accuracy of Customer Information
  * Access to and Rectification of Your Personal Information
  * Vehicle Data Recorders
  * 911 Assist (if equipped)
  * SYNC
  * Location and Global Positioning Systems (GPS) (if equipped)
  * Ford Works (if equipped)
  * Effective Date and Revisions

### _Information about Ford of Canada:_

Ford Motor Company of Canada, Limited (Ford of Canada) is a manufacturer of vehicles, engines, and automotive accessories and a distributor of aftermarket automotive parts and service products. This privacy policy applies to our brands, Ford, the Lincoln Motor Company, Lincoln and Mercury and their associated brands and products, Ford Genuine Parts and Service, Fast Lane Tire & Auto Centre, Roadside Assistance, and Motorcraft. Our automotive products are distributed to you through our network of Ford and Ford Lincoln dealers, independently owned and operated businesses which may have their own privacy policies and procedures. Our affiliated company, Ford Credit Canada Company and its subsidiaries, associates and affiliates (collectively, Ford Credit) provides vehicle financing and related financial products and services. Please contact Ford Credit at its Customer Service Centre, 1-877-636-7316, or click here for more information about Ford Credit and its privacy policy [www.fordcredit.ca](http://www.fordcredit.ca/).

### _How to Contact Us and Concern Resolution:_

If you have any questions, comments, concerns or complaints about privacy and the handling of your personal information, please contact us at our Customer Relationship Centre (CRC), 1-800-565-FORD (3673). We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy and the handling of your personal information and are happy to respond to your questions and comments. If after contacting our CRC you still have unresolved concerns with respect to our handling of your personal information, please write to our Privacy Officer at:

Attention: Privacy Officer

Ford Motor Company of Canada, Limited  
P.O Box 2000  
Oakville, ON, L6K 0C8

If you have completed the above process and we have been unable to resolve your concern, you may file a complaint with the federal Privacy Commissioner of Canada or the appropriate provincial privacy officer. For more information, please go to  <https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/>.

### _Why We Collect and How We Use Customer Information:_

Ford of Canada collects, stores and uses information about you for the following reasons:

  * to establish, maintain and improve our customer relationship with you, improve our products and services, and provide you with offers, incentives, marketing programs or promotional material about us and our automotive products and services, such as coupons, brochures and newsletters
  * to more effectively market to you our vehicles, vehicle parts, accessories and services by better understanding your automotive product and service needs and preferences
  * to assist in administering your vehicle purchase, lease, warranty, any extended service plan, roadside assistance, or ongoing vehicle service, including advising you of any product recalls or customer notifications with respect to your vehicle, arranging for Ford of Canada dealers to obtain required vehicles and parts on a timely basis to meet your needs, and through our CRC working to resolve your concerns
  * to conduct customer surveys and participate in market research studies conducted by third parties
  * to provide you with goods or services you request and respond to your comments, concerns or requests for information, such as through our websites (brochure fulfillment, emails, or other materials) or through our CRC, including identifying you and establishing your ownership of the vehicle or contacting you if required
  * to assist our dealers to meet your automotive product and services needs such as providing assistance where you need to export or import your vehicle
  * to provide you with offers and information about related automotive products offered by others which may be of interest to you
  * to meet our legal obligations, assist in law enforcement purposes, and protect the business interests of Ford of Canada and our customers.

Monitoring of Contacts  
When you contact our CRC or when we contact you, it is our general practice to monitor and/or record such contacts for staff training and quality assurance purposes.

Personal information is retained as long as required to fulfill these purposes. We have established retention policies and procedures to ensure that when the retention period expires, your personal information will be removed from our systems and destroyed in a secure manner.

### _Types of Customer Information We Collect and Use:_

We may collect the following types of customer information about you or relating to your automotive sales or service experience for the purposes set out above:

  * information which enables us to identify and communicate with you including name, address, phone number, e-mail address, language preference, and title
  * information which enables us to offer you products which better meet your needs including demographic such as age, education level, occupation, marital and family status, purchase preferences and interests
  * information about your vehicle ownership including VIN, license plate number, applicable vehicle incentives, new or used, lease or purchase, any trade-in, odometer reading, make, model, model year and vehicle details, recalls, and customer notification programs, your selected dealer, and whether you have disposed of a Ford, Lincoln or Mercury vehicle
  * information about your vehicle service, including warranty and paid repair data, your selected dealer and extended service plan or roadside assistance for your vehicle
  * information you provide us about you and your purchase, lease or service experience and competitive vehicle ownership or purchase intentions through our Customer Viewpoint survey, our websites, test drives or other promotions or incentives, or through our CRC
  * financial and credit information about you shared with us by Ford Credit when you have provided your consent

### _How We Collect Customer Information:_

### Directly From You

We obtain information directly from you such as when you complete our Customer Viewpoint surveys, participate in a contest, test drive, focus group or other research initiative, promotion, campaign or event, purchase roadside assistance or extended service plan or contact our CRC. We may also obtain information directly from you through our websites.

### From Our Dealers

When you acquire a new or Quality Certified Ford, Lincoln or Mercury vehicle from our dealers, the dealer provides us with the following information about you and your vehicle to enable us to administer your purchase:

  * your name, address, telephone number, email address and language preference
  * VIN and vehicle details, odometer reading, sale date, warranty start date
  * Lease or purchase and applicable incentive information
  * Any trade in VIN and odometer reading
  * Extended service plan coverage

When you service your vehicle at our dealers, your dealer may also provide us with information regarding your service experience including your name, contact information, VIN, service date, and transactional information such as repair type, completion date, and odometer reading.

If you do not want us to use this information to contact you for sales or marketing purposes or to request you complete a survey with respect to your experience and would like to limit our use of this information to administration of your vehicle purchase or service, recalls or customer notification programs, warranty, extended service plan, roadside assistance and resolving your concerns, please contact our CRC at 1-800-565-FORD (3673).

### From Ford Credit

When you finance or lease a vehicle from Ford Credit, where you have provided your consent, Ford Credit provides us with your contact information and information about your finance or lease contract so that we may offer you automotive or financial services products that may be of interest to you. Please contact Ford Credit at its Customer Service Centre, 1-877-636-7316, if you no longer wish us to receive any personal information from Ford Credit about you.

### From Other Parties

We may acquire a list of names and addresses, which may include your name and address where you have given your consent, from list vendors to send promotions or product information to the names on the list. We also have relationships with third parties with whom we conduct joint marketing activities such as contests through which we may obtain your name and address and other information about you with your consent. These activities clearly identify the other parties involved and provide information about their privacy practices. Any such other parties are bound by their privacy policy, not ours.

To ensure our database addresses remain accurate, we also obtain address information from third party licensed data providers for National Change of Address and other authorized parties.

### _How We Collect Information on Our Website:_

**When you visit our website, we do not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us.**  Information on our site may be available for you to review without providing us with any personal information. However, you may be unable to participate in certain promotions or receive product information or have a request fulfilled. If you do not agree with our privacy policy, please do not provide us with any personal information through our website.

**

When you visit this web site, other parties such as third-party advertising partners and analytics providers may collect information about your online activity over time and across websites. This information may include identifiers that may permit those parties to serve tailored ads to your device. For more information about third-party advertising partners’ collection and use of such data for interest-based advertising purposes (and opting out of such use), see “Interest-Based Online/Behavioral Advertising” below.

Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret web browser-based “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signals other than cookies, we do not currently respond to undefined “DNT” signals to this website.

Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some functions or services on this websites.

**

### Non-personally Identifiable Information:

Through our websites, we collect non-personally identifiable information. This means that we do not track this information on a basis that identifies you but rather collect this information on an aggregate (or anonymous) basis that includes all site visitors. This information includes tracking the site pages that are visited or the amount of time spent on our site, clicks, page views, and information about your browser/system. Our primary goal in collecting aggregate information is to be able to perform site metrics that allow us to improve the functionality of the website. We collect aggregate information in order to compile aggregate and statistical data to help in website design and to identify popular features and measure site activity to allow us to update our site to better meet user wants and needs. We track page visits, perform site click through analysis, review peak site usage times and analyze layout and design. We may share these site metrics which are not personal information with our affiliated companies, service providers and others.

Our websites may also use session log data and non-personal data for the purpose of performing analytics on the user's experience while visiting the site. This analysis:

  * Is performed on an aggregate level and does not identify you or your information personally
  * Involves the use of a third party vendor acting on our behalf
  * Is performed in order to improve our website and the user experience
  * Includes the use of session and/or persistent cookies to track user movement across this and other Ford websites or to track other events within or across this and other Ford websites

### _Social Sharing / Liking :_

If you visit this website and “like” or share content via our social sharing capability you will be connecting to a third-party social media server (i.e. Facebook.com, Twitter.com). Ford of Canada may track on an aggregate level, the number of items "liked" or items on this website that you choose to share with the third-party social media site.

### _Cookies, Web Beacons and Advertisements_

Our website may use session and persistent “cookies,” session logs, spot light ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags, banner ads or links, third party networks that serve user-requested emails (e.g., a third party email service provider for Tell-a-Friend user-customized emails), and third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as Adobe, DoubleClick, Efficient Frontier, and Google Analytics) to collect aggregate or other non-personally identifiable information about site visitors.

A “cookie” is a small text file that helps us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites. They also allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences. There are a couple different types of cookies.

A “session” cookie is stored only in your computer's working memory (RAM) and only lasts for your browsing session. When you close all your browser's windows, or when you shut down your computer, the session cookie disappears forever.

A “persistent” cookie is stored on your computer's hard drive until a specified date, which could be tomorrow, next week, or 10 years from now. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until either a) they expire, b) they are overwritten with newer cookies, or c) you manually remove them. Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some site functions or features.

This site may use a third party to activate and/or deliver a service, or deliver site functionality such as fulfilling your request for a product or service. In performing this function the third party may place a persistent cookie on your computer or have to gather personal information from you in order to activate and deliver the product or service.

This website may use a third-party click tracking analytics tool (such as Adobe, and Google Analytics) to capture clickthrough statistics.

This website may use spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags which are site instrumentation tools that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times. Emails or electronic newsletters we send may use tools (e.g., pixel tags or web beacons) to gather email metrics and information to improve the reader’s experience such as how many of the emails are opened, if they were printed or forwarded, the type of device (e.g., mobile or PC) from which they were opened, and the city, province, and county associated with the applicable IP address. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a webpage, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon.

When you visit our website the server housing the pages automatically generates a “session log.” We use session logs to help us determine how people travel through our site. In this way, we can structure our pages so that the information most frequently visited is easier to find. By tracking page visits, we can also determine if the information we're providing is being used. The only data gathered is the Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you came (which contains no personal information), the website that referred you, the pages you visited and the date and time of those visits.

If you visit this site with an open ID, you may integrate with third-party social media sites, and we may track on an aggregate level the number of visits to this site with an open ID, the number of items “liked” on this site, or items on this site that you choose to share with a third-party social media site.

Users may be directed to our site via banner ads, site links or QR Codes. Ads, site links or QR Codes may use tools such as cookies or web beacons to deliver metrics on the effectiveness of the ads or links. They do not collect personally identifiable information from the user.

### 
* Interest-Based/Online Behavioural Advertising

_Interest-Based/Online Behavioural Advertising._  On some pages of our site we may allow third-party advertising partners to set web tracking tools (e.g., cookies and web beacons) to collect anonymous, non-personally identifiable information regarding your activities on those pages (e.g., your IP address, page(s) visited, time of day). We may also share such information we have collected with third-party advertising partners. These advertising partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other websites) for purposes of delivering future targeted advertisements to you when you visit other (non-Ford) sites within their networks. This practice is commonly referred to as "interest-based advertising" or "online behavioural advertising."

Pages of our website that collect information that may be used by such advertising partners for interest-based advertising purposes are identified by a link to AdChoices on the page.

_Opting out (site pages)._  If you do not want your browsing while on such pages to be used for interest-based advertising purposes, you may click on the AdChoices link to opt-out of such uses by the listed advertising partner(s). Even if you opt-out through this service, we may still collect non-personally identifiable information regarding your site activities and use it for non-interest-based advertising purposes as described in this privacy policy.

Opting out (advertisements). Advertisements on third-party sites that contain the AdChoices link and that link to this privacy policy may have been directed to you based on anonymous, non-personally identifiable information collected by advertising partners over time and across websites. These advertisements provide a mechanism to opt-out of the advertising partners' use of this information for interest-based advertising purposes. Even if you opt-out through this service, we may still collect and use information from the advertisements for non-interest based advertising purposes, such as to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements.

Opt-out Compliance Service. This site and advertisements on third-party sites that link to this privacy statement use the Evidon assurance service to comply with the cross-industry Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioural Advertising managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada (DAAC) ([www.youradchoices.ca](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)). When you opt-out on site pages or through such advertisements, Ghostery conveys your opt-out election(s) to the applicable advertising partner(s), which then know to place a cookie on your specific computer and browser (and only the specific computer and browser from which you opt out) indicating that you have opted out. If you clear your browser cookies and wish to remain opted out of interest-based advertising, you must opt-out again. The list of our advertising partners may be updated from time to time. To opt-out of internet-based advertising by all DAAC-participating companies, visit [www.youradchoices.ca/](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)

### _Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information on our Website_

There are instances where we request personal information such as name, address, phone number and e-mail address on our site, such as to provide you with a service, coupon, or correspondence (promotions and mailed brochures), during contests or promotions or where you participate in interactive online activities such as e-newsletter registration or Request a Quote, Brochure or Test Drive. At times we conduct voluntary online surveys to obtain your feedback. You may decide to send to us personally identifying informatwww.youradchoices.caion in an email, for example in a message about your Ford product or service. Any personal information collected is used as set out in this Privacy Policy.

Please keep in mind that if you disclose personally identifiable information through a chat room or message board or other public online forum, this information may be collected and used by others.

### _Links to other Websites_

Our website may contain links to other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of all sites which you visit, including those whose links are provided, so that you can understand how those sites collect, use and share your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements, content or data handling practices on other websites.

### _How We Share Customer Information:_

**We do not share, sell or rent the personal information you provide us to third parties for their own independent marketing purposes or use without your consent, as required by applicable privacy laws.**

We may transfer personal information to suppliers, service providers, contractors or agents (including our affiliates acting in this capacity) that perform services on our behalf such as mailing, customer service, call campaigns, marketing, information technology and/or data hosting or processing services or similar services, or otherwise to collect, use, disclose, store or process personal information on our behalf for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Some of these suppliers, service providers, contractors, agents or affiliates may be located outside of Canada, including in the United States and the Philippines. Specifically, we use a service provider in the United States to store and process all your personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, including providing information technology services to provide you with marketing material and surveys. We may also use service providers in the United States to conduct call campaigns. We require our suppliers, service providers, contractors and agents who have access to your personal information in connection with its processing or use for us to keep the information confidential and they are not permitted to use your personal information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for us. Reasonable contractual or other measures we may take to protect your personal information while processed or handled by suppliers, service providers, contractors or agents are subject to legal requirements in Canada, the United States and other foreign countries applicable to them, for example, lawful requirements to disclosure personal information to governmental authorities in those countries.

To improve our products and services, we share your name, contact information and vehicle details with third parties who contact you to conduct market research studies on our behalf or on an industry wide basis and are contractually bound to only use your personal information for that purpose.

We share with your Ford or Ford and Lincoln dealer contact information that you have previously provided to your dealer, updated for accuracy, if we have more accurate information from you or a third party licensed data provider for National Change of Address, and information that you provide to our CRC where necessary to assist you to resolve any issues or concerns you may have. We may also share your personal information with Ford or Ford and Lincoln dealers from whom you have requested an online service through us such as a test drive or quote to enable them to meet your needs. If you have not specified a Ford or Ford and Lincoln dealer or you have not purchase or leased a vehicle from an existing dealer, we may share with your consent with the Ford or Ford Lincoln dealer who has responsibility for the market area in which you reside the personal information which you have provided to us, such as when you enter a contest, so that the dealer may contact you. Collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by the dealer(s) will be subject to the dealer's privacy policy.

You may wish to use the same account identification (e-mail address) for one or more Ford of Canada or Ford Motor Company websites (including syncmyride.com) or you may choose to create a new account. To facilitate this for you, when you provide your email address to us on registration with a Ford of Canada website, we check whether we already have an account with this email address and advise you. When you register with a Ford Motor Company website, we share with Ford Motor Company whether a Ford of Canada website account exists for the email address you have entered so that Ford Motor Company can advise you whether you may use an existing account.

We may also disclose your personal information where we are required or permitted by law to do so. Where required by law, we will release personal information only to the extent required. In addition, personal information may be disclosed or transferred to a third party during the course of, or completion of, a change in ownership of or the grant of a security interest in, all or a part of Ford of Canada through, for example, an asset or share sale, or some other form of business combination, merger or joint venture, provided that such party is bound by appropriate agreements or obligations and required to use or disclose your personal information in a manner consistent with the use and disclosure provisions of this Privacy Policy, unless you consent otherwise.

### _How Is Privacy Managed at Ford and Ford/Lincoln Dealers in Canada:_

Each dealership operation is a separate legal entity, independent from Ford of Canada. As such, each dealership has its own privacy practices and Ford of Canada is not responsible for these privacy practices. We recommend that you review the privacy practices of the Ford of Canada Dealer with whom you are dealing to ensure that you understand their privacy practices and procedures. When completing a purchase or lease agreement with a Ford of Canada Dealer you may be provided with information relating to the Dealership's privacy practices and explaining that personal information that you provide may be shared with Ford of Canada which will be used by Ford of Canada as described in this Privacy Policy.

### _How You Can Opt Out of Further Marketing Communications:_

You may decide that you do not want us to send you marketing or promotional communications. Our marketing emails to you will include an unsubscribe which we will process within ten business days. For other marketing communications, such as direct mail, please contact our CRC at 1-800-565-FORD (3673). You may notify us at any time and your direction will be effective within 30 days. You may, however, no longer receive some offers or information of value to you. It is important for you to know that even if you choose to withdraw your consent, we will continue to use and disclose your personal information to meet legal and contractual obligations such as honour your warranty and send you recall notifications.

### _Security and Accuracy of Customer Information:_

Safeguarding your personal information is important to us. We use systems, policies and procedures to maintain accuracy of information and to protect your personal information which is stored in the United States and the Philippines from loss, misuse, theft or alteration.  **Customer personal information is only accessible by appropriate personnel who have a business need for this information.**  We provide training to educate our personnel about our polices and procedures and appropriate handling of personal information. When you send personal information to our website, we use "Secure Socket Layers" (SSL) to protect your data. SSL is encryption technology that helps safeguard your personal information against misuse by unauthorized individuals.

We make reasonable efforts to keep your information up to date and accurate such as by using third party licensed data providers for National Change of Address. We encourage you, however, to contact our CRC at 1-800-565-FORD (3673) as often as necessary to keep your name, address and vehicle ownership information up to date.

### _Access to and Rectification of Your Personal Information:_

You may contact our CRC at 1-800-565-FORD (3673) to review, correct, or update certain of your personal information which is easily accessible to our service representatives at the CRC. The information which may be accessible to our service representatives includes your name, address, current or past Ford or Lincoln vehicle ownership, vehicle information such as recalls, and previous contacts to the CRC.

If you wish us to undertake a more comprehensive search of our files, you may notify us in writing at:

_Attention: Privacy Officer_

Ford Motor Company of Canada, Limited  
P.O Box 2000  
Oakville, ON, L6K 0C8

You will be asked for sufficient personal information for us to verify your identity and the details about the personal information you are interested in prior to us processing your request. Information which may be accessible includes your contact information, demographic information, information about your current or past Ford or Lincoln vehicle ownership or service, vehicle information including recalls and owner notifications, financial and credit information about you shared with us by Ford Credit when you have provided your consent, and other information you may have provided to us. We will be unable to provide you with information which is exempt from disclosure such as personal information about another person, privileged information or confidential commercial information.

### _Vehicle Data Recorders:_

Service data recorders in your vehicle are capable of collecting and storing diagnostic information about your vehicle. This potentially includes information about the performance or status of various systems and modules in the vehicle, such as engine, throttle, steering or brake systems. In order to properly diagnose and service your vehicle, Ford Motor Company, Ford of Canada and service and repair facilities may access or share vehicle diagnostic information through a direct connection to your vehicle when diagnosing or servicing your vehicle. Additionally, when your vehicle is in for service or repair, Ford Motor Company, Ford of Canada and service and repair facilities may access or share among them data for vehicle improvement purposes.

Your vehicle is also equipped with an event data recorder (EDR). The main purpose of an EDR is to record, in certain crash or near crash-like situations such as an air bag deployment or hitting a road obstacle; this data will assist in understanding how a vehicle's systems performed. The EDR is designed to record data related to vehicle dynamics and safety systems for a short period of time, typically 30 seconds or less. The EDR in the vehicle is designed to record such data as:

  * how various systems in your vehicle were operating;
  * whether or not the driver and passenger seatbelts were buckled/fastened;
  * how far (if at all) the driver was depressing the accelerator and/or the brake pedal;
  * how fast the vehicle was traveling; and
  * where the driver was positioning the steering wheel.

These data can help provide a better understanding of the circumstances in which crashes and injuries occur. Note: EDR data is recorded by your vehicle only if a nontrivial crash situation occurs; no data is recorded by the EDR under normal driving conditions and no personal data or information (e.g. name, gender, age, and crash location) is recorded (see limitations regarding 911 Assist privacy information below). However, parties such as law enforcement could combine the EDR data with the type of personally identifying data routinely acquired during a crash investigation.

To read data recorded by an EDR, special equipment is required and access to the vehicle or the EDR is needed. In addition to the vehicle manufacturer, other parties, such as law enforcement, that have such special equipment, can read the information if they have access to the vehicle or the EDR.  **We do not access EDR information without obtaining consent, unless pursuant to court order or where required by law enforcement, other government authorities or other third parties acting with lawful authority.**  Other parties may seek to access the information independently of us.

### _911 Assist (if equipped):_

Including to the extent that any law pertaining to EDR applies to SYNC© or its features, please note the following: once 911 Assist (if equipped) is enabled (set ON), 911 Assist may, through any paired and connected cell phone, disclose to emergency services that the vehicle has been in a crash involving the deployment of an airbag or, in certain vehicles, the activation of the fuel pump shut-off. Certain versions or updates to 911 Assist may also be capable of being used to electronically or verbally provide to 911 operators the vehicle location (such as latitude and longitude) and/or other details about the vehicle or crash or personal information about the occupants to assist 911 operators to provide the most appropriate emergency services. **If you do not want to disclose this information, do not activate the 911 Assist feature. See your SYNC© supplement for more information. Note: Vehicles equipped with the MyKey feature may be capable of overriding the 911 Assist settings and turning 911 Assist ON, even if it was previously set to Off. IF you do not want to disclose this information, do not enable MyKey.**

### _SYNC©:_

When a cellular phone is connected to SYNC, the system creates a profile within your vehicle that is linked to that cellular phone. This profile is created in order to offer you more cellular features and to operate more efficiently. Among other things, this profile may contain data about your cellular phone book, text messages (read and unread), and call history, including history of calls when your cellular phone was not connected to the system. In addition, if you connect a media device, the system creates and retains an index of supported media content. The system also records a short development log of approximately ten minutes of all recent system activity. The log profile and other system data may be used to improve the system and help diagnose any problems that may occur. The cellular profile, media device index, and development log will remain in the vehicle unless you delete them and are generally accessible only in the vehicle when the cellular phone or media player is connected. If you no longer plan to use the system or the vehicle, we recommend you erase all stored information. System data cannot be accessed without special equipment and access to the vehicle’s SYNC module. Ford Motor Company and Ford of Canada will not access the system data for any purpose other than as described absent consent, a court order, or where required by law enforcement, other government authorities, or other third parties acting with lawful authority. Other parties may seek to access the information independently of Ford Motor Company and Ford of Canada.

### _Location and Global Positioning Systems (GPS) (if equipped)_

Your vehicle may contain a global positioning system (GPS) or may utilize the GPS in your connected wireless device in some instances. GPS may be used to determine your vehicle’s physical location, travel direction, and speed, and to record this information over time to provide GPS-based services. This information may be recorded in your vehicle and may be accessed by Ford of Canada or Ford Motor Company to provide services you request, with your consent, or in accordance with a court order or where required by law enforcement, other government authorities, or other third parties acting with lawful authority. Other parties may seek to access the information independently of Ford Motor Company and Ford of Canada.

### _Ford Works (if equipped):_

The Ford Works Solutions computer includes a feature "Delete Stored Items" which will delete all of your stored data and return the system to its original state. All personal files/programs, navigation data and paired phones/devices will be removed from the system. In the event that you sell your vehicle, you may wish to use this feature to clear the computer of all personal data.

### _Effective Data and Revisions:_

This Privacy Policy is effective  **August 27, 2014.**  Occasionally we may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our practices. If we update this statement, the new statement will be posted to the website ten days prior to the changes taking effect. You may determine when this policy was last updated by referring to the modification date at the bottom of the policy.

_Last Modified: August 27, 2014_
